<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Craig Citro</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/feeds/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.craigcitro.org/</id><updated>2016-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>New site</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/new-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2016-01-09:new-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm finally finding time to start straightening up my web presence, and step
one involves updating this site. In the process, I'm setting up a blog. This
includes a few of the old posts from my blogspot blog, as well as one post I
wrote a year ago but apparently never posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come -- but if there's anything you've asked me for a link to, ask
again and I'll put it up here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Managing Bookmarks</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/managing-bookmarks.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2014-12-22:managing-bookmarks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like everyone, I often run into interesting content that I don't have time to
read then and there. Bookmarks to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I end up with a
mountain of bookmarks. After years of experimenting, I've finally come up with
an effective system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bookmark things in chrome (or your browser of choice) as you find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly once a month, make a few folders to try and do some basic grouping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About once every 6 weeks, remember that you'd seen an interesting link on a
specific topic, but you can't seem to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At about three months, realize you've now bookmarked more content than you
could read in a month. Declare bankruptcy, delete all links you can't read in
that sitting, and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;future work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a later post, I plan to apply this same technique to handling email.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Math Jokes</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/math-jokes.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2009-12-04:math-jokes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw these on &lt;a href="http://mathoverflow.net/questions/1083/do-good-math-jokes-exist"&gt;mathoverflow&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The primary reason Bourbaki stopped writing books was the realization that
Lang was one single person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A paper should be like a miniskirt: short enough to be interesting and long
enough to cover the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Great quote</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/great-quote.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2009-11-18:great-quote.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From Chris: "apple is like the really hot girl u didnt know was whack"&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Lockhart's Lament</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/lockharts-lament.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2009-06-28:lockharts-lament.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon a link to
&lt;a href="http://www.maa.org/devlin/LockhartsLament.pdf"&gt;Lockhart's Lament&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should stop and read this right away, if you haven't already. It's a
fairly harsh and biting attack on the state of math education (and more
specifically K-12 math education) in the US. His main point is that the focus
of the K-12 math curriculum has essentially nothing to do with the actual
practice of mathematics, which is true. It's not perfect, but there's almost
nothing I actually disagree with in it -- its only real sins are sins of
omission. Here are my thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockhart does an excellent job of talking about the problem, but says
nothing about ways to solve the problem. I strongly agree that the state of
education in general, and math education in particular, is fairly bad in the
US. However, just saying that over and over isn't going to fix anything. I'd
be curious to hear what he thinks about ways to fix the system, other than the
obvious -- just overhaul the whole thing. I'll save most of my ranting for
another post, save for this: I don't see how we're going to fix the system
until we find a way to make being a teacher -- especially a teacher at a
public school -- an actually desirable job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Lockhart also gives a bit more credit to teaching in other areas
than they deserve. He speaks as though the curriculum in english or the
sciences is great -- clearly he didn't have my middle and high school
experience. :) That said, it does fit with his primary theme -- I think there
was much more similarity between my high school english classes and the job of
a literary critic than between my high school math classes and the job of a
mathematician, especially a research mathematician in pure math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that Lockhart also underplays the value of some amount of rote
exercises, especially for younger math students. However, I think the point
that he's trying to make is that rote exercises without any motivation
whatsoever are pointless -- and I agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockhart seems to take the point of view that the reason for doing math is
to do research in pure math. He doesn't seem to take much time to talk about
math as a tool for physics or engineering, which is just silly. Of course, his
attacks still apply -- my experience is that students of engineering take
calculus classes because they're required, but don't actually understand why
they're doing it until later on. Sadly, because they had no idea what they
were doing or why, they also generally don't remember any of the techniques
they learned, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to say again, though, that I loved this article. Even if there were
things that were missing, there was so much good in it. Of course, I don't
seem to be the only one ... here's a link to
&lt;a href="http://scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=410"&gt;the blog post&lt;/a&gt; that first pointed me to
the article, and another link with info
&lt;a href="http://www.maa.org/devlin/devlin_03_08.html"&gt;about Lockhart himself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>