<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Craig Citro</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/feeds/craig-citro.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Get that job at Google! (mathematician edition)</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/get-that-job-at-google-mathematician-edition.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;People often ask me for advice about how to get a job at Google, especially
research mathematicians. This post is basically the common parts from my
emails on the topic, for better discoverability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This often breaks down into one of two questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I be happy working as a software engineer at (a place like) Google?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should I do to get ready for the interview?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this was from a discussion with William Stein, who used it in a
&lt;a href="https://sagemath.blogspot.com/2016/01/mathematics-graduate-school-preparation.html"&gt;nice and related blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going into software (esp. from academia)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main piece of advice to potential Google applicants is "start writing as
much code as you can, right now." The main goal here is to find out whether
you'd actually &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; working for a company like Google, where a large chunk
of your job is coding in front of a screen. I've had several friends from math
discover (the hard way) that they don't really enjoy full-time programming
(any more than they enjoy full-time teaching?), but only once they were 6
months into a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of this is really a question about your own personality: if you're the
type of person that finds engrossing new problems everywhere you look, then
industry may well be a lot of fun. On the other hand, if you've got an area of
research that you love, and you can't imagine working on anything else,
academia is the place to be ... unless that area of research happens to be ad
click prediction, in which case you can pick either. :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start throwing things on github now. Potential interviewers are &lt;em&gt;going&lt;/em&gt; to
check out your github profile; having some cool stuff at the top is great, but
seeing a regular stream of commits is also a useful signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liken the interview process at the top companies as much like applying to
grad school: it's quite hard to say "I'm going to go to &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; school,"
because there's just too much randomness in the process. Instead, you should
apply to at least 3 good companies, and have a fallback or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone has no real experience in any language, I generally say "start
with Java." Some people will tell you it's a boring language, but it's used
lots of places, and as they say, "no one ever got fired for choosing Java."
Plus, Java is a lot
&lt;a href="http://blog.paralleluniverse.co/2014/05/01/modern-java/"&gt;snazzier&lt;/a&gt; than it
used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google interview mechanics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there's lots of good advice out there -- I think
&lt;a href="http://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/2008/03/get-that-job-at-google.html"&gt;Steve Yegge's post&lt;/a&gt;
(from which I stole the title here) gives a great overview. I'll give a few
pieces of advice that he doesn't highlight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the interview, think out loud as much as possible. Honestly, the
interviewers are much more interested in &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you work on the problem than
what you end up coding. This is sometimes hard to do (especially without
feeling a little self-conscious when you're stuck), but it's well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between now and the interview, spend as much time as you can coding. I know
this sounds obvious, but it's easy to lose track of, especially if you're busy
with your current job. All the stuff you read online will tell you that you
need to know every algorithms book backwards and forwards; the most
complicated data structure I used in my interview was a linked list. It's good
to have a bunch of that in your head, but it's more important to make it clear
that you're comfortable actually coding. Multiple folks I've referred got
tripped up by this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've never done a software interview before, try to get some friends to
do mock interviews. This will be good for thinking out loud, but also to get
you in the habit of writing code at a board. It's not something many people do
often, especially in these days of omnipresent computing ... I've written more
code via cellphone than whiteboard in the last year, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2016-08-05:get-that-job-at-google-mathematician-edition.html</guid></item><item><title>LA food recs</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/la-food-recs.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It's been forever since I lived in LA, but I still long for some of the food.
One of my friends asked for some food recs, so I'm recording them here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amazing eats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amandine&lt;/strong&gt;: go and get the french toast, and then get anything else that
sounds good. It's my absolute favorite french toast in the known universe,
which is a strong compliment. Every pastry I had was good; I remember the
coffee being good, but that was before I lived in Seattle, so that's harder to
say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bay Cities Italian Deli&lt;/strong&gt;: it's a big deli that also makes sandwiches; you
can go in and take a number, or just order online like a sane person. Lines
that can sometimes put paseo to shame. the sandwiches are incredible. (I
always got the godmother, I think?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abbot Kinney Pizza&lt;/strong&gt;: they do a bunch of awesome pizzas with a bagel crust,
and it's fantastic. If you can, go to the one in venice (they usually have
more pizza options on hand).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;India Sweets &amp;amp; Spices&lt;/strong&gt;: another not-fancy-but-delicious place, down in
Culver City; it's also primarily a grocery store that happens to sell amazing
food. (vegetarian)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pita Pockets&lt;/strong&gt;: this one is up in the Valley, so if you're not already
headed that way, may be further than you want to go. But holy cow, the laffa
wraps are out of this world. They also have amazing hummus, and I drool
thinking about their falafel laffa wrap with hummus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&amp;amp;O Trattoria&lt;/strong&gt;: this is a fantastic place to go if you're looking for a
MASSIVE amount of fresh garlic rolls and pasta. It's tasty, but maybe not the
best pasta in the universe, with self-service wine at the table. If you're
going with a bunch of friends, this one's hard to beat, and you can take a
nice walk on the beach in Venice after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desserts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinkberry&lt;/strong&gt;: this is the place that made tart yogurt famous; I don't know
if it's still up to its former glory, but it was reeeeeally good when it first
came along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scoops&lt;/strong&gt;: this used to only be waaaaaay over on the east side of LA, but
is now apparently on the westside. One of the most amazing ice cream shops
I've been to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susie Cakes&lt;/strong&gt;: this was the first place I had a really, really amazing
cupcake. Some of their cupcakes and cookies are out of this world, and others
are just so-so. So take that one with a grain of ... sugar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2016-06-14:la-food-recs.html</guid></item><item><title>New site</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/new-site.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm finally finding time to start straightening up my web presence, and step
one involves updating this site. In the process, I'm setting up a blog. This
includes a few of the old posts from my blogspot blog, as well as one post I
wrote a year ago but apparently never posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come -- but if there's anything you've asked me for a link to, ask
again and I'll put it up here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2016-01-09:new-site.html</guid></item><item><title>Managing Bookmarks</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/managing-bookmarks.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like everyone, I often run into interesting content that I don't have time to
read then and there. Bookmarks to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I end up with a
mountain of bookmarks. After years of experimenting, I've finally come up with
an effective system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bookmark things in chrome (or your browser of choice) as you find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly once a month, make a few folders to try and do some basic grouping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About once every 6 weeks, remember that you'd seen an interesting link on a
specific topic, but you can't seem to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At about three months, realize you've now bookmarked more content than you
could read in a month. Declare bankruptcy, delete all links you can't read in
that sitting, and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;future work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a later post, I plan to apply this same technique to handling email.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2014-12-22:managing-bookmarks.html</guid></item><item><title>Math Jokes</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/math-jokes.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw these on &lt;a href="http://mathoverflow.net/questions/1083/do-good-math-jokes-exist"&gt;mathoverflow&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The primary reason Bourbaki stopped writing books was the realization that
Lang was one single person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A paper should be like a miniskirt: short enough to be interesting and long
enough to cover the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2009-12-04:math-jokes.html</guid></item><item><title>Great quote</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/great-quote.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From Chris: "apple is like the really hot girl u didnt know was whack"&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2009-11-18:great-quote.html</guid></item><item><title>Lockhart's Lament</title><link>http://www.craigcitro.org/lockharts-lament.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon a link to
&lt;a href="http://www.maa.org/devlin/LockhartsLament.pdf"&gt;Lockhart's Lament&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should stop and read this right away, if you haven't already. It's a
fairly harsh and biting attack on the state of math education (and more
specifically K-12 math education) in the US. His main point is that the focus
of the K-12 math curriculum has essentially nothing to do with the actual
practice of mathematics, which is true. It's not perfect, but there's almost
nothing I actually disagree with in it -- its only real sins are sins of
omission. Here are my thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockhart does an excellent job of talking about the problem, but says
nothing about ways to solve the problem. I strongly agree that the state of
education in general, and math education in particular, is fairly bad in the
US. However, just saying that over and over isn't going to fix anything. I'd
be curious to hear what he thinks about ways to fix the system, other than the
obvious -- just overhaul the whole thing. I'll save most of my ranting for
another post, save for this: I don't see how we're going to fix the system
until we find a way to make being a teacher -- especially a teacher at a
public school -- an actually desirable job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Lockhart also gives a bit more credit to teaching in other areas
than they deserve. He speaks as though the curriculum in english or the
sciences is great -- clearly he didn't have my middle and high school
experience. :) That said, it does fit with his primary theme -- I think there
was much more similarity between my high school english classes and the job of
a literary critic than between my high school math classes and the job of a
mathematician, especially a research mathematician in pure math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that Lockhart also underplays the value of some amount of rote
exercises, especially for younger math students. However, I think the point
that he's trying to make is that rote exercises without any motivation
whatsoever are pointless -- and I agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockhart seems to take the point of view that the reason for doing math is
to do research in pure math. He doesn't seem to take much time to talk about
math as a tool for physics or engineering, which is just silly. Of course, his
attacks still apply -- my experience is that students of engineering take
calculus classes because they're required, but don't actually understand why
they're doing it until later on. Sadly, because they had no idea what they
were doing or why, they also generally don't remember any of the techniques
they learned, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to say again, though, that I loved this article. Even if there were
things that were missing, there was so much good in it. Of course, I don't
seem to be the only one ... here's a link to
&lt;a href="http://scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=410"&gt;the blog post&lt;/a&gt; that first pointed me to
the article, and another link with info
&lt;a href="http://www.maa.org/devlin/devlin_03_08.html"&gt;about Lockhart himself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Craig Citro</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2009-06-28:lockharts-lament.html</guid></item></channel></rss>