<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Craig Citro</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/feeds/food.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.craigcitro.org/</id><updated>2016-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>LA food recs</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/la-food-recs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2016-06-14:la-food-recs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been forever since I lived in LA, but I still long for some of the food.
One of my friends asked for some food recs, so I'm recording them here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amazing eats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amandine&lt;/strong&gt;: go and get the french toast, and then get anything else that
sounds good. It's my absolute favorite french toast in the known universe,
which is a strong compliment. Every pastry I had was good; I remember the
coffee being good, but that was before I lived in Seattle, so that's harder to
say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bay Cities Italian Deli&lt;/strong&gt;: it's a big deli that also makes sandwiches; you
can go in and take a number, or just order online like a sane person. Lines
that can sometimes put paseo to shame. the sandwiches are incredible. (I
always got the godmother, I think?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abbot Kinney Pizza&lt;/strong&gt;: they do a bunch of awesome pizzas with a bagel crust,
and it's fantastic. If you can, go to the one in venice (they usually have
more pizza options on hand).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;India Sweets &amp;amp; Spices&lt;/strong&gt;: another not-fancy-but-delicious place, down in
Culver City; it's also primarily a grocery store that happens to sell amazing
food. (vegetarian)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pita Pockets&lt;/strong&gt;: this one is up in the Valley, so if you're not already
headed that way, may be further than you want to go. But holy cow, the laffa
wraps are out of this world. They also have amazing hummus, and I drool
thinking about their falafel laffa wrap with hummus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&amp;amp;O Trattoria&lt;/strong&gt;: this is a fantastic place to go if you're looking for a
MASSIVE amount of fresh garlic rolls and pasta. It's tasty, but maybe not the
best pasta in the universe, with self-service wine at the table. If you're
going with a bunch of friends, this one's hard to beat, and you can take a
nice walk on the beach in Venice after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desserts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinkberry&lt;/strong&gt;: this is the place that made tart yogurt famous; I don't know
if it's still up to its former glory, but it was reeeeeally good when it first
came along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scoops&lt;/strong&gt;: this used to only be waaaaaay over on the east side of LA, but
is now apparently on the westside. One of the most amazing ice cream shops
I've been to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susie Cakes&lt;/strong&gt;: this was the first place I had a really, really amazing
cupcake. Some of their cupcakes and cookies are out of this world, and others
are just so-so. So take that one with a grain of ... sugar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Cambridge food recs</title><link href="http://www.craigcitro.org/cambridge-food-recs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Craig Citro</name></author><id>tag:www.craigcitro.org,2008-09-05:cambridge-food-recs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cambridge, MA has one of the best concentrations of great eateries of any
place I've ever lived; here's the list of my favorites, dated from the last
time I sent it along to someone. (I know at least Herrell's is gone, which is
a crime against humanity.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darwin's&lt;/strong&gt;: my favorite place in Cambridge. There are two of them in
Cambridge, one on Mt. Auburn, one on Cambridge St. The one on Cambridge St. is
a bit bigger, but generally a bit busier. Get a sandwich, get coffee, and get
a coconut macaroon. Eat the macaroon while it's still cold. It's unbelievable.
(I recommend ordering at least two macaroons per person, based on personal
experience. Last time I was in Boston, I brought home 12 of them ... and we'd
eaten them all in less than two days.) They also have amazing breakfast food,
but only if you get there early enough. If you only go to Harvard Square for
one meal, this is it. The last time I went to Boston, I had the cab drop me
off at Darwin's. (If you do only have one meal in Harvard Square, don't miss
Herrell's on the same trip.) I have only had one bad experience -- Asia's
first sandwich there was on &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; bad bread (I think it was too dry, but I
don't remember what kind it was). We went up and got her a different kind of
bread, moved the sandwich over, and it moved up to one of the five best
sandwiches she'd ever had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Helmand&lt;/strong&gt;: This is also in Cambridge, and easiest to get to by
driving. Make a reservation, but it's not expensive. In fact, given how
amazing the food is, it's probably the best deal in Cambridge. Everything on
the menu is amazing. Not in the best part of town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Herrell's Ice Cream&lt;/strong&gt;: This is some of the best ice cream anywhere, ever.
They tend to make weird flavors (like "earl grey"), which you should taste if
they sound at all good. People in Boston will try to tell you that JP Licks is
better, but they're just plain wrong. The hot fudge is not to be missed, if
you like chocolate at all. If you don't like chocolate, consider upgrading
your taste buds! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veggie Planet&lt;/strong&gt;: vegetarian pizza that's fantastic. If you like spicy
food, I &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; recommend the Unsafe 'n' Sound, or the Safe 'n' Sound if you
don't. There's a Mexican bean pizza that's also pretty darn good, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b. good&lt;/strong&gt;: A "healthy" burger joint, which is pretty damn tasty. A much
lighter meal than Mr. Bartley's, and better in several ways -- much more
unique, to say the least. Look at the left wall when you're standing by the
counter to order -- there's a "monthly special" which is usually freaking
fantastic. This is (to date) still the best white bean burger I've had
anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr. Bartley's Burgers&lt;/strong&gt;: Huge, tasty burgers. Go at an off hour if you
can, because it gets &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; busy and noisy. Don't miss the sweet
potato fries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry></feed>