<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Craig Citro</title>
    <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Craig Citro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 Craig Citro</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get that job at Google! (mathematician edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2016-08-05-software-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2016-08-05-software-jobs/</guid>
      <description>People often ask me for advice about how to get a job at Google, especially research mathematicians. This post is basically the common parts from my emails on the topic, for better discoverability.
This often breaks down into one of two questions:
  Would I be happy working as a software engineer at (a place like) Google?
  What should I do to get ready for the interview?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA food recs</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2016-06-14-eating-in-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2016-06-14-eating-in-la/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been forever since I lived in LA, but I still long for some of the food. One of my friends asked for some food recs, so I&#39;m recording them here:
Amazing eats   Amandine: go and get the french toast, and then get anything else that sounds good. It&#39;s my absolute favorite french toast in the known universe, which is a strong compliment. Every pastry I had was good; I remember the coffee being good, but that was before I lived in Seattle, so that&#39;s harder to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2016-01-09-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2016-01-09-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m finally finding time to start straightening up my web presence, and step one involves updating this site. In the process, I&#39;m setting up a blog. This includes a few of the old posts from my blogspot blog, as well as one post I wrote a year ago but apparently never posted.
More to come &amp;ndash; but if there&#39;s anything you&#39;ve asked me for a link to, ask again and I&#39;ll put it up here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2014-12-22-managing-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2014-12-22-managing-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Like everyone, I often run into interesting content that I don&#39;t have time to read then and there. Bookmarks to the rescue!
But then I end up with a mountain of bookmarks. After years of experimenting, I&#39;ve finally come up with an effective system.
The System   Bookmark things in chrome (or your browser of choice) as you find them.
  Roughly once a month, make a few folders to try and do some basic grouping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Jokes</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2009-12-04-math-jokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2009-12-04-math-jokes/</guid>
      <description>I saw these on mathoverflow:
 The primary reason Bourbaki stopped writing books was the realization that Lang was one single person. A paper should be like a miniskirt: short enough to be interesting and long enough to cover the subject.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great quote</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2009-11-18-great-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2009-11-18-great-quote/</guid>
      <description>From Chris: &amp;ldquo;apple is like the really hot girl u didnt know was whack&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockhart&#39;s Lament</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2009-06-28-lockharts-lament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2009-06-28-lockharts-lament/</guid>
      <description>I recently stumbled upon a link to Lockhart&#39;s Lament.
You should stop and read this right away, if you haven&#39;t already. It&#39;s a fairly harsh and biting attack on the state of math education (and more specifically K-12 math education) in the US. His main point is that the focus of the K-12 math curriculum has essentially nothing to do with the actual practice of mathematics, which is true. It&#39;s not perfect, but there&#39;s almost nothing I actually disagree with in it &amp;ndash; its only real sins are sins of omission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge food recs</title>
      <link>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2008-09-05-eating-in-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigcitro.org/posts/2008-09-05-eating-in-cambridge/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge, MA has one of the best concentrations of great eateries of any place I&#39;ve ever lived; here&#39;s the list of my favorites, dated from the last time I sent it along to someone. (I know at least Herrell&#39;s is gone, which is a crime against humanity.)
  Darwin&#39;s: my favorite place in Cambridge. There are two of them in Cambridge, one on Mt. Auburn, one on Cambridge St. The one on Cambridge St.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>